（ナレーション）帝光(ていこう)中学校
バスケットボール部
The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
部員数は100を超え
全中三連覇を誇る 超強豪校
An incredibly strong team with over one hundred members and three consecutive championship wins.
その輝かしい歴史の中でも
特に“最強”と呼ばれ—
Even within that brilliant history,
a group of five prodigies known as the
"Generation of Miracles" stood above the rest.
無敗を誇った10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた世代は—
“キセキの世代”と言われている
が “キセキの世代”には
奇妙なうわさがあった
However, there was a strange rumor concerning the Generation of Miracles.
誰も知らない 試合記録もない
Despite being relatively unknown
and lacking a game record,
にもかかわらず—
there was one more member
recognized by the five prodigies.
天才５人が 一目置いていた
選手がもう１人
幻のシックスマンがいた と
A phantom sixth man.
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Translation Check   AMS
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
Editing      AMS
Dakara itta janai ka
Didn’t I already tell you?
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
Yowasa wo uri ni shitatte
That even if you use your weakness as a selling point.
Timing       sangofe
Mae ni nanka susume ya shinaindaze
You won’t progress at all.
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
Nee hakanai jibun
Hey, my ephemeral self.
Enshutsu shitatte dare mo mukandou
Even if I produce, nobody'll care.
QC      muyg, sangofe
ninjacloud
Kodoku ga sainamu yoru ni datte
Even on nights when I’m tormented by my loneliness,
Karaokes      KmE
Asu machi wabiru hikari ga aru
there’s a light that’s impatiently waiting for tomorrow.
Tsuyogaru yowai jibun wo mitomerareru tsuyosa wo
I’m weak and just putting up a strong front, but I will start
Hajimerunda yareru mon sa
gathering the strength I need to admit that I can do it.
Soko kara mae wo mui chatte
From there, I’ll look straight ahead.
Aruke
And I’ll walk,
Hashire
I’ll run,
nando demo
no matter how many times it takes.
Choushi hazure no koe datte ii sa
Doesn’t matter if I’m out of tune.
Cho
u
shi
ha
zu
re
no
ko
e
da
t
te
i
sa
Cho
u
shi
ha
zu
re
no
ko
e
da
t
te
i
sa
Sore ga doushitan datte
What’s wrong with that?
So
re
ga
do
u
shi
ta
n
da
t
te
So
re
ga
do
u
shi
ta
n
da
t
te
Encoding      Your Mom
Sakebunda ore no ban da can you do it?
Now shout, it’s my turn, can you do it?
Sa
ke
bu
n
da
o
re
no
ba
n
da
can
you
do
it?
Sa
ke
bu
n
da
o
re
no
ba
n
da
can
you
do
it?
Suru to dou darou nan datte
When I do it, how’s that?
Su
ru
to
do
u
da
ro
u
na
n
da
t
te
Su
ru
to
do
u
da
ro
u
na
n
da
t
te
Kowaku nanka naku natten ze
Somehow my fears are all gone.
Ko
wa
ku
na
n
ka
na
ku
t
te
n
ze
Ko
wa
ku
na
n
ka
na
ku
t
te
n
ze
Kyou ga wagami da
It’s my day today...
Kyo
u
ga
wa
mi
da
Kyo
u
ga
wa
mi
da
I
can
do
it
You
can
do
it
We
can
do
it
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
（黒子(くろこ)）フッ！
（笠松(かさまつ)）何っ！？
What?
（笠松）なっ…
（火神(かがみ)）フッ！ ぬあっ！
（小金井(こがねい)）あっ
（武内(たけうち)）うああ…！
All right!
（火神）よっしゃあ！
おっ…？ うおっ！
（黄瀬(きせ)）フッ
でやあっ！
I can't say the same for girls,
オレ 女の子には
あんまっスけど—
but I've never failed to return a favor on the court.
バスケで お返し忘れたことは
ないんスわ
Bring it on.
テメエ 上等だ！
I'll admit you have potential,
（黄瀬）ポテンシャルは認めるけど
オレには 遠く及ばない
but you're still far below me.
君が どんな技をやろうと—
No matter what you throw at me,
with one look, I'll return it twice as good.
見れば オレは
すぐに倍返しできる
You can struggle, but you'll never beat me.
（黄瀬）どうあがいても
オレには勝てねえっスよ
ハハハハ
ワリー ワリー
Sorry, sorry.
I'm just so happy.
ちょっと うれしくってさ
勝てねェぐらいが ちょうどいい！
It's better if I can't win.
Besides, thanks to you, now I know your weakness.
おかげで分かったしな
オマエの弱点
あ… 弱点？
What weakness?
In other words...
（火神）つまり！
（黒子）あっ…
This guy is your weakness.
こいつだろ！ オマエの弱点！
Episode 4
Take Care of the Counter Attack!
Kagami's powerless against Kise,
（日向(ひゅうが)）火神でも歯が立たない
黄瀬の弱点が…
but his weakness is...
Aside from passing, the weakest guy on the court, Kuroko?
パス回し以外
コート上で最弱の—
黒子君？
So?
It's true Kurokocchi's style is the only one I can't imitate.
確かに 黒子っちのプレーだけは
見ても 無理っス
But what does that change?
けど それで 何が
変わるっていうんスか？
（記録係）第１クオーター終了！
休憩２分です！
End of the first quarter!
We'll have a two minute break!
It changes everything.
変わるさ！ 第２クオーターで
ホエヅラ かかせてやる！
We'll bring you to tears in the second quarter.
Seirin
Kaijo
An eight point difference.
Seirin
Kaijo
（海常(かいじょう)部員１）８点差か…
Seirin
Kaijo
（海常部員２）
誠凛(せいりん) なかなかやるじゃん
Seirin
Kaijo
Seirin's not bad.
Seirin
Kaijo
What the hell are you doing?!
（武内）ったく 何やってんだ！
Seirin
Kaijo
もっと点差 つけられたぞ！
They're closing the gap!
（海常選手たち）はい！！
Yes, sir!
Your fundamentals suck!
（武内）基本がなってねえんだよ！
ハンズアップ！
Hands up! Screen out! Rebound!
スクリーンアウト！
リバウンド！
（海常選手たち）はい！
Yes, sir!
（武内）高さが勝ってんだから
リバウンド 抑えてくんだよ！
You're taller than them, so grab those rebounds!
Yes, sir!
（海常選手たち）はい！
I see. Yeah, that could work.
（リコ）なるほど うん…！
ソレ いけるかも
Kagami, it looks like you've finally cooled down.
火神君も やっと
頭 冷えたみたいね
No, I was always—
（火神）いや オレは最初から…
（日向･伊月(いづき)）
超 ムキになってたよ！
You were really pissed!
But Kuroko and Kagami,
けど 黒子君と火神君
２人の連係が大事よ
your coordination will be key.
Can you do it?
これ… できる？
まぁ なん… とか…
Yeah...
Probably...
ギョッ！
You bastard, where did that come from?
テメ！ 何 いきなり…！
You want to beat Kise, don't you?
黄瀬君を倒すんでしょ？
Of course I do!
ったりめーだ！！
Well, then.
んじゃあ まあ…
Let the second quarter begin!
（審判）
第２クオーター 始めます！
（リコ）逆襲よろしく！
Take care of the counter attack!
（海常部員たち）押〜せ 押せ押せ
押せ 押せ 海常！
Do it, do it, do it, do it, Kaijo!
Go!
（福田(ふくだ)）行け〜！
（河原(かわはら)）押せ〜！
Get them!
Go and get them, Seirin!
（３人）行け 押せ 誠凛！！
（黄瀬）でやっ！
（日向）うっ… フッ！
（森山(もりやま)）あっ！
Seirin
Kaijo
Kaijo's defense is still man-to-man.
（日向）海常 ディフェンスは
マンツーマンのまま…
Something's changed, right?
何か 変わったんスよね？
Just another drive?
（黄瀬）ただのドライブ？
また フェイダウェイとか…？
Maybe another fadeaway?
He's coordinating with Kurokocchi!
（黄瀬）
黒子っちと 連係で!?
ハァ… ハァ フッ！
Seirin
Kaijo
Yes!
（リコ）よっし！
（小金井）あっはは！
Nice shot!
（土田(つちだ)）ナイッシュー！
（黄瀬）またスか！？ 同じ手は…
Again? It won't work this time!
（降旗(ふりはた)）
来たぁ！ スリーポイントー！！
All right! A three pointer!
Seirin
Kaijo
A five point gap!
Seirin
Kaijo
（福田）５点差！
Seirin
Kaijo
フッ ちょっとは
見直したかなあ １年 ２人…
Have you changed your minds, first ye—
Nice!
（伊月）ナイス！
All right, defense!
（火神）よっしゃ ディフェンス！
Hey!
（日向）おい！
No. 4's really going for it.
（小堀(こぼり)）
相当打ち込んでるな あの４番
We should be worried about Kagami.
それよか 火神だ
抜くパターンに—
He and Kuroko have started passing back and forth to each other.
黒子との 中継パスを
組み込んできやがった
パス もらうだけだった
火神が—
Kagami's started passing the ball instead of just receiving it.
パスもするように
なっただけだろ？
Does that really change much?
そこまで変わるか？
It changes a whole lot, dumbass!
えらい違いだよ バカ！
Kuroko's passing and Kagami's one-on-one
今までは 黒子のパスと
火神のワンオンワンは—
were two separate offensive patterns.
あくまで 別々の
オフェンスパターン…
They only had two options.
ただの二択にすぎなかった
Now that they pass to each other,
だが パスがつながったことで
お互いの選択肢が増えて—
they both have more options,
which makes their offense stronger.
前より一段 上の攻撃力になる！
And Kise can't copy Kuroko, the linchpin of the play.
（リコ）
しかも その要である黒子君は—
黄瀬君が動きを コピーできない
It's his bane.
いわば 天敵！
Kagami and Kuroko.
火神君と 黒子君—
With those two, we can...
この２人なら…
Well, we can probably make it.
まぁ たぶん… ギリで いける…
ハァ ハァ ハァ
黒子っち
Kurokocchi...
Kise, you're strong.
（黒子）黄瀬君は 強いです
I'm powerless, and Kagami can't stand against you.
ボクはおろか
火神君でも歯が立たない
けど 力を合わせれば—
But when we work together,
we have a fighting chance.
２人でなら 戦える
You really have changed, Kurokocchi.
やっぱ 黒子っち 変わったっスね
帝光時代に
こんなバスケはなかった
We never played basketball like this at Teiko, but
けど—
you still can't stop me.
そっちもオレを止められない
I will be the winner!
そして 勝つのはオレっスよ！
Seirin
Kaijo
It's true I can't copy your coordination,
Seirin
Kaijo
黒子っちの連係を お返しすんのは
できないっスけど—
Seirin
Kaijo
but since you'll lose your effectiveness after 40 minutes,
黒子っちが フルに40分
持たない以上—
you'll lose this game in the second half!
結局 後半 ジリ貧に
なるだけじゃないスか
Not so fast.
そうでもねーぜ
なあっ！
What?
Kuroko's on Kise?
黒子が 黄瀬のマーク！？
Who's the guy on Kise?
（海常部員１）
黄瀬についてんのって
えっと…
Isn't he the guy that passes a lot?
（海常部員２）すげえパス
してたヤツだよな？
I don't remember him doing anything other than pass.
（海常部員３）いや でもさぁ—
パス以外
目立ってなかったような…
He doesn't stand a chance!
（海常部員たち）
相手に なるわけねえ！
I never dreamed we'd play together like this, Kurokocchi.
まさか 夢にも
思わなかったっスね
黒子っちと こんなふうに
向き合うなんて
Neither did I.
ボクもです
I don't know what you're up to,
一体 どういうつもりか
知らないスけど—
but you can't stop me, Kurokocchi!
黒子っちに オレを止めるのは
無理っスよ！！
Wrong. We're not gonna stop you.
違うね 止めるんじゃなくて…
獲るのよ！
We're taking the ball!
What? A back tip!
（黄瀬）バックチップ！？
They took advantage of the second I hesitated!
火神のヘルプで
ひるんだ一瞬を…！？
It doesn't matter how amazingly you play against us.
（火神）オマエがどんな すげえ技
返してこようが 関係ねえ
We're trying to let you through!
抜かせるのが 目的なんだからな
（海常部員たちのざわめき）
（河原）ナイッシュー！
Nice shot!
ええぃ…
Damn it, a simple double team would've been better.
クソ ただのダブルチームのほうが
まだマシだぞ
Not even Kise can react in time to
（リコ）あの影の薄さで
後ろから こられたら—
an invisible guy coming up behind him.
いくら黄瀬君でも
反応できないでしょ！
I just won't run by you, then.
（黄瀬）そんなの 抜かなきゃ
いいだけじゃないスか
No one said I couldn't shoot
誰も言ってないスよ
a three pointer!
スリーポイントがないなんて！
（火神）フンッ！ てぃっ！！
They got me.
（黄瀬）やられた！
平面は 黒子っちが—
Kurokocchi's covering below,
and Kagami's covering up top.
高さは 火神が
カバーするってことスか…！
An outside shot takes too much movement.
（笠松）外からのシュートは
モーションが かかっからな…！
These guys are a pain!
やっかいだぜ やっぱりこいつら！
しかも この流れを
作ってんのは 黒子だ
Kuroko's the one making this happen.
He's the most worthless guy on the court, and he can't do anything by himself, but...
コートで一番のヘボで—
１人じゃ 何にもできねえはずが
信じられねえ！！
I don't believe this!
（火神）グッ 速攻！
（黄瀬）ぬおお！
Fast break!
Kuroko!
黒子君！
（ホイッスル）
（審判）レフェリータイム！
Referee time out!
（日向）黒子！
Kuroko!
Are you okay, Kuroko?
（日向）大丈夫か？ 黒子！
I feel lightheaded.
（黒子）フラフラします
Get a first aid kit!
救急箱 持ってきて！
大丈夫かよ…
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
大丈夫です
まだまだ試合はこれからで…
The game is just getting start—
しょう…
Kuroko!
黒子ォ〜！！
They're finished.
（笠松）終わったな
It's not what should have happened though.
不本意な結末だが
Without that first year duo,
あの１年コンビが 欠けた以上
あとは 点差が開くだけだ
the difference in score will only widen.
Kurokocchi...
（黄瀬）黒子っち…
What are we gonna do?
（伊月）どうする…？
（リコ）黒子君は もう出せないわ
Kuroko can't play anymore.
We'll have to make do with the players we have left.
残りのメンバーで
やれることを やるしかないでしょ
Make do?
（河原）やれることって…
（福田）黒子いないと キツくね？
Isn't this gonna be tough without Kuroko?
The second years will be our offensive core.
オフェンスは
２年生 主体でいこう
It's only the second quarter,
まだ第２クオーターだけど
離されるわけには いかないわ
but we can't let them get too far ahead of us.
早いけど“勝負所”よ 日向君
I know it's early, but it's game time, Hyuga.
Okay.
Kise will just copy you,
（リコ）黄瀬君に返されるから
火神君 オフェンス禁止！
so don't play offense, Kagami.
Focus on defending.
ディフェンスに専念して
Do everything you can to stop Kise from scoring.
全神経を注いで 黄瀬君の得点を
少しでも抑えて
そんな それで
大丈夫なんですか？
Are you sure that will work?
大丈夫だって ちっとは信じろ
It'll be fine. Have some faith.
でも！
But...
I said it'll be fine, dumbass.
大丈夫だっつってんだろ
ダアホ！
Listen to your seniors once in a while or I'll kill you.
たまには 先輩の言うこと
聞けや 殺すぞ
First years should show more respect for their seniors.
（日向）ったく 今時の１年は
どいつもこいつも…
もっと敬え！ 先輩を！
そして 平伏せえ〜っ！！
Get on your knees!
You're showing your true colors, Captain.
スイッチ入って 本音 漏れてるよ
キャプテ〜ン
Don't worry about him.
気にすんな クラッチタイムは
ああなんの
He's always like that during clutch time.
When he speaks his mind, he won't miss many of his shots.
とりあえず 本音 漏れてる間は
シュート そうそう落とさないから
Leave the offense to him.
オフェンスは任せて
オマエはディフェンス—
You just defend like your life depends on it.
死に物狂いで いけ
A screen! And at just the right time.
（森山）スクリーン！ シブい
タイミングで やりやがって…！
Bastard!
（小掘）こいつ…
He's usually a normal guy,
（リコ）優しいときは 並の人
but when he gets going, he's amazing!
スイッチ 入るとすごい！
けど 怖い！
But also scary!
The multiple personality clutch shooter, Hyuga Junpei!
二重人格クラッチシューター
Hyuga Junpei
2nd Year
#
日向順平！
Take that.
ざまあ！
（リコ）沈着冷静 慌てません
Calm and collected, he never loses his cool!
He may seem cool and in control, but he has a sense of humor!
クールな司令塔 かと思いきや
まさかのダジャレ好き！
Izuki Shun!
伊月 俊！
Izuki Shun
2nd Year
#
Nice icy hot Salon-pass.
ヤベェ キタ コレ
Oh man, that was funny!
Hardworking, heroic, and strong
（リコ）仕事キッチリ
縁の下の力持ち！
with a voice no one has heard,
でも声 誰も聞いたことない！
Mitobe Rinnosuke!
Mitobe Rinnosuke
2nd Year
#
水戸部(みとべ)凛之助(りんのすけ)！
He can do everything and nothing!
何でもできるけど
何にもできない
A jack of all trades and a master of none!
（リコ）ミスター器用貧乏！
（小金井）ん？
（リコ）小金井慎二！
Koganei Shinji!
Koganei Shinji
2nd Year
#
You're so mean.
ひでえ〜
Unfortunately, every last one of them never gives up!
あいにくウチは
１人残らず 諦め悪いのよ
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
（高尾(たかお)）
ぬうっ… ハァ ハァ
ハァ ハァ
くっそー 信号待ちで
ジャンケンなのに…
Damn it, we were supposed to switch at the lights.
It's a bike trailer.
（小学生）リアカーだ…
You haven't pedaled once!
（高尾）
オマエ １回も こいでなくね？
Of course I haven't.
（緑間(みどりま)）そんなの 当然なのだよ
Today's "Oha-Asa" horoscope predicted
なぜならば 今日の
“おは朝”の星座占い—
the greatest of days for Cancers like me.
オレのかに座は
１位だったのだから
（高尾）
それ関係あんの それ！？
What does that have to do with this?
Anyway, if we're coming all the way out here to see a practice game,
つーか わざわざ 練習試合なんか
見るくらいだから—
相当 できんだろうな？
your middle school teammates better be good!
オマエの同中(おなちゅう)！
It's the copycat and the invisible man.
（緑間）
マネっ子と 影 薄い子だね
（高尾）それ 強いのお？
Are they good?
（緑間）それより速く！
試合が終わってしまう
Hurry up, or the game will be over.
It's your fault for reading horoscopes!
（高尾）オマエが
占いなんか 見てたからだろ！
ぐおお！ フンッ！
They're not as good without Kuroko,
（笠松）黒子が
いたときほどじゃねえが—
チームオフェンスも やりやがる
but their offense isn't bad.
They're putting No. 4's shooting ability to good use.
４番のシュート力
うまく いかしてんな
There's a minute and a half left in the second quarter.
（土田）第２クオーター…
残り １分半
This isn't easy.
（日向）
やっぱ しんどいっつうの…
On top of that, we're not as strong without Kuroko.
黒子 抜きで
パワーダウンしてるし…
Seirin
Kaijo
I'm starting to lose focus.
Seirin
Kaijo
オレの集中力も
切れてきちゃったし…
Seirin
Kaijo
I don't think we can make a comeback.
てか 逆転とか
できる気 しねえ…
Coach, isn't there anything we can do?
（河原）カントク
何か手はないんですか？
They don't have any energy left after the first half's pace.
前半のハイペースで—
策とか仕掛けるような体力
残ってないのよ
If only we had Kuroko...
せめて黒子君がいてくれたら…
Very well.
（黒子）分かりました
（リコ）え？
Good morning.
おはようございます
I'll be going then.
じゃ… 行ってきます
Hey, wait.
（リコ）
ちょっと…！ いやいやいや
What are you talking about?
何 言ってんの！
But you just told me to go.
でも… 今 行けって
カントクが…
I didn't tell you to do that.
言ってない！
It just slipped out.
たらればが 漏れただけ！
Then I'm going.
（黒子）じゃあ 出ます
（リコ）オイ！
Hey!
（黒子）ボクが出て 戦況を
変えられるなら お願いします
If I can change anything by going out there, please.
Besides...
それに…
I promised Kagami I would be his shadow.
約束しました
火神君の影になると
はぁ… 分かったわ
Fine.
ただし ちょっとでも
危ないと思ったら—
But if I think you're in trouble,
I'm switching you out immediately.
すぐ 交代します！
Let's go.
行くぜ
はい
Yeah.
Didn’t I already tell you?
That even if you use your weakness as a selling point,
you won’t progress at all.
Hey, my ephemeral self.
Even if I produce, nobody'll care.
We were just getting used to him,
慣れかかってたのに
また元の薄さに 戻ってやがる！
Even on nights when I’m tormented by my loneliness,
but now he's back at full power.
there’s a light that’s impatiently waiting for tomorrow.
It must be because he stayed out the last two quarters.
第２ 第３クオーター まるまる
引っ込んでいたからか！？
I’m weak and just putting up a strong front, but I will start
Seirin
Kaijo
Whoa, seriously?!
（海常部員１）うぉぉ マジか
80 対 82！？
Seirin
Kaijo
80-82?
Seirin
Kaijo
They're catching up!
（海常部員２）差が詰まってる！
Seirin
Kaijo
gathering the strength I need to admit that I can do it.
Seirin
Kaijo
だはっ… ハァ ハァ ハァ
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ
From there, I’ll look straight ahead.
And I’ll walk, I’ll run, no matter how many times it takes.
You're kidding!
（海常部員１）って…
（海常部員２）ウソだろ？
Doesn’t matter if I’m out of tune.
What’s wrong with that?
Now shout, it’s my turn, can you do it?
Seirin
Kaijo
They're tied!
Seirin
Kaijo
（海常部員）同点！？ 同点だ！
Seirin
Kaijo
It's tied!
Seirin
Kaijo
Seirin finally caught up!
When I do it, how’s that?
誠凛が ついに追いついたぞ！
Somehow my fears are all gone.
It’s my day today, I can do it.
（黄瀬）同点…
We're tied?
You can do it.
We can do it!
Kise!
黄瀬！！
黒子！！
Kuroko!
He's even stronger?
（火神）ここにきて
まだ 強くなんのか！？
Did he see through Kuroko?
黒子も 見きったってのかよ！？
I won't lose.
オレは負けねえっスよ 誰にも
Not to anyone.
Not even Kurokocchi.
黒子っちにも
This isn't good.
ヤベェな
Give it your all, everyone.
全員 気ぃ入れろ
こっから試合終了まで
第１クオーターと同じ—
This'll be just like the first quarter from here on out.
A back and forth run-and-gun game!
点の取り合い…
ランガン勝負だ！！
ディフェンス 急げ！
Hurry up, defense!
Hyuga, hurry!
日向君 急いで！
水戸部君 ポスト走る！
Mitobe, post up!
Kagami!
（小金井）火神〜！！
（土田）行け 行け〜！
Go, go!
What are you doing?
何をやってるんだ！
戻り 遅いだろうが〜！！
You're slow getting back!
Two minutes and eleven seconds left.
（リコ）残り ２分11秒
（黄瀬）でやあ！
（火神）ぬあっ！
（ホイッスル）
（海常部員）また同点！！
They're tied again!
なっ… しぶとい！
トドメさすぞ！
These resilient bastards!
Finish them!
There's no time left! Get them!
時間ねえぞ！ 当たれ！
If we don't take the ball here, it's over!
ここでボール取れなきゃ
終わりだぞ！
Kagami...
（黒子）火神君
（火神）はっ！
If we can get the ball,
ここを取れれば—
there's one more thing we can do Kise can't copy.
黄瀬君に コピーされない手が
もう１つあります
It's a simple strategy that will only work once, though.
１回きりの
単純な手ですけど…
There's less than ten seconds left.
（リコ）残り 10秒 切った…
We don't have the energy left to play overtime.
もう ウチに 延長戦を戦う
体力はない！
Good defense!
（誠凛選手２）守れ 守れ！
（誠凛選手３）守るんだー！
（誠凛選手１）
ディフェンス位置につけ！
Don't let them score!
You can't just defend! Take the ball!
守るんじゃダメ！！ 攻めて！！
Worthless piece of shit!
（日向）この ヘタレ！
ああ！ しまった！
Crap!
（火神）でえい！
うわぁ 取った！
He got it!
マジかよ！
Seriously?
ぬおおお！ どあ〜っ！
Don't let them through!
抜かせるな！！
（火神）黒子！
Kuroko!
Kurokocchi can't shoot!
黒子っちにシュートはない！
２人だったら—
With only two of them, he'll have to pass it back to Kagami!
火神にリターンするしか
ないスよ…！
He shot it?
シュート！？
No...
…じゃねえ！
It's an alley-oop!
アリウープだ！！
（黄瀬）させねえっスよ！！
I won't let you do that!
くうっ…！
He's still climbing? How far will he go?
（黄瀬）まだ？ いつまで…！？
We jumped at the same time, but I'm falling first.
同時に跳んだのに
先に オレが落ちてる
How can you stay in the air so long?
何なんだ オマエの
その宙にいる長さは…！？
It's a simple strategy
１回きりの
単純な手ですけど…
that will only work once though.
I don't need you to the return the favor!
テメーのお返しは
もう いんねーよ！ なぜなら…
Because...
We just have to score a buzzer beater.
ブザービーターで
決めちゃえばいいんです
This ends now!
（火神）
これで 終わりだからな！！
Seirin
Kaijo
だって悔しくて まじ情けなくて
datte kuyashikute maji nasakenakute
It's frustrating, it's really shameful.
止まらない涙を笑いたきゃ笑え
tomaranai namida wo waraitakya warae
If you want to laugh at my unstoppable tears, go ahead and laugh.
不公平すぎだろ 生まれつき違うんだ
fukouheisugi daro umaretsuki chigaunda
Isn't it too unfair? We're different the moment we're born.
遠くなる背中を指くわえて見てる
tooku naru senaka wo yubi kuwaete miteru
I can only look enviously at your back getting further away.
「天才なんだよ」追いつけやしない
"tensai nanda yo" oitsuke ya shinai
"You're a genius", there's no way I can catch up.
自分の限界値を勝手に決めてた
jibun no genkaichi wo katte ni kimeteta
I willfully set my limits on myself.
本当は知ってる 本当のことを
hontou wa shitteru hontou no koto wo
I really know it, I know the truth.
誰より努力してる姿
dare yori doryoku shiteru sugata
I know I worked harder than anyone else.
見えないふりしてんのは
mienai furi shiten no wa
I'm just pretending to not see it.
わかってるんだ わかってるんだ だけど
wakatterunda wakatterunda dakedo
I know it, I know it, but...
どうにもこうにもなんないからとか
dou ni mo kou ni mo nannai kara to ka
I say it won't work or be like this and
なんとかかんとか言って
nantoka kantoka yutte
so and so and so on.
みんなも自分も自分も自分も
minna mo jibun mo jibun mo jibun mo
Fooling everyone and myself and myself
上手にだまくらかして
jouzu ni damakurakashite
and myself skillfully.
一体全体僕は何を誇れるだろう
ittaizentai boku wa nani wo hokoreru darou
What in the world can I be proud of?
あの日のボクは僕を嗤うかな
ano hi no boku wa boku wo warau ka na
Will that me someday laugh at the me right now?
もっと もっと 空は碧いはずさ
motto motto sora wa aoi hazu sa
The sky is supposed to be much much bluer.
Now, start it right away!!
Next Episode
（黄瀬）黒子っち 話があるんス
Kurokocchi, I have to ask you something.
Why did you just disappear then?
なんであのとき
姿 消したんスか？
（黒子）よく言われます
（黄瀬）そうじゃなくて！！
I get that a lot.
That's not what I meant!
I'm not sure.
（黒子）分かりません
ただ ボクはあの頃—
All I know is I hated basketball at the time.
Episode 5
Your Basketball
バスケが嫌いだった